Deities of Cathaysia
Vast clouds in my breath
Boundless dust on my finger
I go through five thousand years
Bright eyes are opened in the beginning of chaos
Pangu spilts apart Heaven and Earth with a swing of giant axe
To extend the territory to seek an audience with the Three Sage Kings
(Three Sage Kings: Surien, Fuxi and Shennong)
The Emperor of Heaven collects classics in Lang Huan Palace
How many chapters throughout the ancient China
Tree Ruomu in the Eastern Heaven
(Ruomu: a kind of divine tree in the ancient)
and Dragon Zhulong in Mt. Zijin
warms up the hearts of Chinese nations
Houyi pulls back the cord to shoot the Sun
Whatever a boundless ground cannot be out of heroes’ sight
Suiren uses the light of stars into fire to shine the country
Shennong tastes hundreds of herbs and drinks water from thousands of rivers
Nuwa chops off feet of the huge turtle Ao
to set up the foundation of the nation
Now still it is my straight spine
In chaos Chiyou fights against Huangdi
He dead in the battle however his brave soul still guards the country
Glede as flag
Huangdi rides chariot to the battlefront
On the ninety-thousand-acre plain
I am the one to begin the Age of Pantheon
I visit several mountains and pass by painted walls
get to classics of inscriptions
drink up Heaven and Earth with heat in the throat
Xingtian dances with Ganqi in Mt. Changyang
Goddess of the Empyrean live in the Heaven
Red carp jumps through the Dragon Gate
Cangjie creates characters to civilize the world
Goodness always dies fast
Quyuan dreams of returning to Xiangjiang River
He is remembered from generation to generation
The melodious sound of lyre holds Goddess Luo and God River spellbound
Is the jade pendant still in Luoyang?
Huge waves crash nosily on the vast Donghai Sea
Nezha rides on hot wheels in the center of lotus
Leizhenzi is appointed the General due to his braveness
Yunzhongzi climbs over the clouds to realize time really flies
King Wen dreams of white tiger entering his room in the dead of night
Magpies fly to show the appearance of a wise king
Every deity bows to Jiangziya and call him the King
He is the one to start the Legend of Deification
How far away has Xihe’s Golden Car left?
Where is Wangshu riding the Moon to?
I have been up to the Milky Way
And down to the desert
But who to sing out the story in Twelve Towers
(Twelve Towers is the mansion of gods)
During generations of gods
the hardship is twisted into cloisters
After thousands of years
It becomes into wrinkles of my hands
The history of heroes develops in the red painted Hall
Also in this groundless world
As well as light of stars to shine brightly
Who is raising whips to open the new era in Cathaysia
Huge waves crash nosily on the East China Sea
Who is on the front list of Legendary of Deification
Passing by Kunlun Mountains
To warm the wine in the pot
I write down and recite many classics with drunkenness
I read thousands of books to live a legendary life
traced back to five thousand years
let me name myself as “the Hero of Cathaysia”